<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Luis Orduz - Notes</title><link href="https://luord.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://luord.com/feed/notes.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://luord.com/</id><updated>2024-12-08T00:19:00-05:00</updated><icon>https://luord.com/assets/img/site/favicon.png</icon><entry><title>Automated initial OS setup</title><link href="https://luord.com/notes/gxemsl2/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-12-08T00:19:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-12-08T00:19:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Luis Orduz</name></author><id>tag:luord.com,2024-12-08:/notes/gxemsl2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend I finally got done something I probably should have back since I
got my first computer nearly two …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend I finally got done something I probably should have back since I
got my first computer nearly two decades ago: a script to automate the initial
setup of a new OS installation. After all, I've been using Linux for most of
that time and it wasn't even that hard to do. I guess I never felt fully
confident in my setup itself to bother replicating it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest hurdle was that I have also always wanted synchronization
of my most valuable files across all my devices... Which I finally got done
this time too in a simple enough way, just how I like it. Sure, it's always
been possible, but nice tools like &lt;a href="https://rclone.org/"&gt;rclone&lt;/a&gt; bisync and
&lt;a href="https://tailscale.com/"&gt;tailscale&lt;/a&gt; make it significantly easier nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The script is &lt;a href="https://github.com/luord/scripts/blob/master/setup.sh"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
It ended up being a handy opportunity to practice my Bash too, and it's
working pretty well for a minimalist like me. Still, suggestions are welcome!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Notes"></category></entry><entry><title>Type variance</title><link href="https://luord.com/notes/gnmokz2/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-08-22T18:45:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-08-22T18:45:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Luis Orduz</name></author><id>tag:luord.com,2023-08-22:/notes/gnmokz2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spent a while fixing up the &lt;a href="https://luord.com/2023/03/01/genetic/"&gt;genetic&lt;/a&gt; algorithm I wrote a while ago; up
until the version that is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spent a while fixing up the &lt;a href="https://luord.com/2023/03/01/genetic/"&gt;genetic&lt;/a&gt; algorithm I wrote a while ago; up
until the version that is up now, I didn't really like how it looked and the reason was
the type hints. It simply didn't click to me why the classes from the implementation
weren't compatible with the protocols in the definition and why I had to create the
type variables (which I find really ugly, and hopefully won't be required anymore in the near
future). Reading up on how to improve it led me to the concept
of variance, of which I only had a vague memory from college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing this note to ensure it doesn't become a vague memory again:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If something cannot be replaced whatsoever, either by subclass or superclass, it's deemed
&lt;em&gt;invariant&lt;/em&gt; in its context. An example is &lt;abbr title="Being"&gt;identity&lt;/abbr&gt;: It makes much more sense to compare a movie
with another movie instead of with a song, even if both cinema and music are considered arts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If something can be replaced by a subclass, it's deemed &lt;em&gt;covariant&lt;/em&gt; in its context.
An example is &lt;abbr title="Having"&gt;possession&lt;/abbr&gt;: If you need something with a camera, then any standalone camera,
smartphone or tablet will do. A telescope, however, might not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If something can be replaced by a superclass, it's deemed &lt;em&gt;contravariant&lt;/em&gt; in its context.
An example is &lt;abbr title="Doing"&gt;action&lt;/abbr&gt;: If you can run, it follows that you can do something that only
needs for you to walk. Conversely, just because I see you walking I can't assume you can run
a marathon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="Notes"></category></entry><entry><title>Asinine awards</title><link href="https://luord.com/notes/gjc26d2/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-01-24T11:07:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-24T11:07:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Luis Orduz</name></author><id>tag:luord.com,2023-01-24:/notes/gjc26d2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The biggest movie award nominations came out today and to the surprise of nobody, the year's
mediocre critical darling of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The biggest movie award nominations came out today and to the surprise of nobody, the year's
mediocre critical darling of choice got the most nods.
I actually thought it was passable when I first watched it, but quite a few people
called it awesome enough times to make me watch it a second time, to see if I had
missed something. It only made me find it even more pointless and boring, and I ended
up hating it and lowered the original rating I gave it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But really, the worst sin of these awards is the total snubbing of "The Northman",
which deserved at the very least a Best Director nomination. And while I'm very happy
for "Top Gun: Maverick", "All Quiet on the Western Front", "Elvis" and, specially, "Elvis"'s
frontman Austin Butler getting the recognition they of course deserve, his nomination
only reminds me of how Taron Egerton was ignored three years ago for "Rocketman" while
one of the worst performances I've ever seen (admittedly, by an otherwise good actor)
not only got nominated but won. Really, it was
the 2020 Best Actor shenanigans what made me lost what little faith I still had back then
for awards, so at this point I'm just beating a dead horse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that said, credit where it's due: Certain uncomfortably revisionist movie everyone was calling
a shoo-in for multiple nominations too was ignored, so that automatically means
the academy has at the very least a saner head on its shoulders than some other award voters.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Notes"></category></entry><entry><title>AI Sadness</title><link href="https://luord.com/notes/gjb22t2/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-01-22T22:35:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-22T22:35:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Luis Orduz</name></author><id>tag:luord.com,2023-01-22:/notes/gjb22t2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well damn, I was tentatively excited about everything going on regarding large language models
and how they're being used, until …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well damn, I was tentatively excited about everything going on regarding large language models
and how they're being used, until today it was brought to my attention how they behave
when the questions are political in nature. Safe to say, impartial they're not, and the excitement
I used to feel instantly became dread. The only silver lining I see is the belief
that the people who would use these models to confirm their biases would already do so in other ways,
and the people who know better would know not to treat them as source of truth regarding political
issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, that thought did not make me feel better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Notes"></category></entry><entry><title>Created a miniblog</title><link href="https://luord.com/notes/gj7j7k2/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-01-20T15:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-20T15:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Luis Orduz</name></author><id>tag:luord.com,2023-01-20:/notes/gj7j7k2/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a way to write more in my site, and in general, I've decided to properly set the
&lt;a href="https://luord.com/category/notes/"&gt;notes category …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As a way to write more in my site, and in general, I've decided to properly set the
&lt;a href="https://luord.com/category/notes/"&gt;notes category&lt;/a&gt; of this blog as a microblog "separated" from the
main blog. Had to create some plugins for &lt;a href="https://getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; to
accomplish it, and included the cool way to create slugs I read about in
&lt;cite class="h-cite u-in-reply-to"&gt;&lt;a class="u-url p-name" href="https://brandur.org/fragments/base32-slugs"&gt;
this great blog post&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;span class="p-author"&gt;Brandur Leach&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make sure whoever subscribes to the main blog doesn't get this more
"stream of thought" bite-size content, the posts in this category are excluded from the main
feed; it has its own feed anyway.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Notes"></category></entry><entry><title>Adding IndieWeb stuff to my blog.</title><link href="https://luord.com/notes/g53io62/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-06-10T23:44:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-06-10T23:44:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Luis Orduz</name></author><id>tag:luord.com,2021-06-10:/notes/g53io62/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Added microformats, Webmentions, POSSE, backfeed and WebSub support to my blog. In fact, this note was syndicated automatically by &lt;a href="https://brid.gy"&gt;https …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Added microformats, Webmentions, POSSE, backfeed and WebSub support to my blog. In fact, this note was syndicated automatically by &lt;a href="https://brid.gy"&gt;https://brid.gy&lt;/a&gt;. Now waiting for Webmentions to display them.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Notes"></category></entry></feed>